Guide to the World Federation of Trade Unions Records
World Federation of Trade Unions Records
- 1947-1950 (Box 2)
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    "Executive Committee meeting - Point 4 of the draft agenda - General report of information on the activity of the WFTU since the Lind World Trade Union Conference," May 19-24, 1950, 145 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    "Executive Committee meeting - Point 9 of the draft agenda - The tasks and methods of the WFTU's propaganda work - Rapporteur: S. Rostovsky, Secretary, WFTU," May 19-24, 1950, 67 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    "Executive committee meeting - Speech of Comrade Rostovsky on 'The Tasks and Methods of the WFTU's propaganda work," May 19-24, 1950, 15 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Committee meeting - Report by the Executive Bureau on the attitude of the Central Council of the Trade Unions of Yugoslavia - Point 3 of the draft agenda," May 19-24, 1950, 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Committee meeting - The problems of unemployment and full employment - Point 6 of the draft agenda," May 19-24, 36 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    "Executive Committee meeting - Report of the consultative conference of the Trade Unions Internationals (trade departments of the WFTU) - Rapporteur: B. Gebert, Secretary of the WFTU - Point 9 of the draft agenda," May 19-24, 1950, 15 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Committee - Activity and tasks of the WFTU in the fight for trade union unity - Rapporteur: B. Frachon, France - Point 6 of the draft agenda," May 19-24, 1950, 24 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WFTU Executive Bureau meeting - Item 2 - Administration of the trade department and creation of new ones - Situation of the Metal Workers Trade Department - Rapporteur: H. Jourdain," December 1-7, 1950, 21 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 2 - Administration of the trade union departments and creation of new ones - Situation of the Maritime and Port Worker's Trade Union International - Rapporteur: A. Fressinet," December 1-7, 1950, 13 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WFTU Executive Bureau meeting - Item 3 - WFTU Review - 'World Trade Union Movement' - Rapporteur: S Rostovsky," December 1-7, 1950, 22 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Meeting of the Executive Bureau of the WFTU - Item 4 - Report on the trade union situation in Africa - Rapporteur: A. Dialio," December 1-7, 1950m 15 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    "WFTU Executive Bureau meeting - Item 7 - Information for Trade Union Centres a) proposal from the Pancrypian Federation of Labor," December 1-7, 1950, 4 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WFTU Executive Bureau meeting - Item 7 - Information for Trade Union Centres c) decision of the General Council of Histradrut (State of Israel)," December 1-7, 1950, 4 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WFTU Executive Bureau meeting - Item 7 - Information for Trade Union Centres d) Statement on the Secretariats conversations with the representative of the Burmese unions," December 1-7, 1950, 4 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
- 1951-1953 (Box 3)
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 1 of the agenda - Strengthening of worker's united action and the development of actions for the defense of their economic and social interests - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant," July 2-6, 1951, 49 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 2 of the agenda - Opposing America's remilitarization of Japan - Reporter: Liu Ning," July 2-6, 1951, 10 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 3 of the agenda - Report on the activity of the Textile Worker's Trade Department - Reporter - A. Burski," July 2-6, 1951, 17 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 3 of the agenda - Report on the activity of the Miners' Trade Department - Rapporteur: H. Turrel," July 2-6, 1951, 15 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Bureau meeting - Item 4 of the agenda - Information on Social Security," July 2-6, 1951, 6 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Executive Bureau meeting - Information on the WFTU delegation to Israel," July 2-6, 1951, 6 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    "General Council meeting - General Report of Activity, Volume I," November 15-21, 1951, 74 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    "General Council meeting - General Report of Activity, Volume II," November 15-21, 1951, 74 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    "General council meeting - Official texts published since the 2nd WTU Congress Milan, July 1949," November 15-21, 1951, 231 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    "WFTU General Council - Point 3 - General report of activity of the WFTU - Rapporteur Louis Saillant, General Secretary, WFTU," November 15-21, 1951, 30 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "General council Speech by Comrade W.W. Kaznetsov on point 4 of the agenda," November 15-21, 1951, 12 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WFTU General Council - Point 4 - Workers unity in the struggle to raise living standards and against the economic and social consequences of the policy of war preparations - Rapporteur: Benoit Frachon," November 15-21, 1951, 33 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    "Executive Bureau meeting - Point I - The present struggles of the workers and the defense of trade union rights - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant," June 9-15, 1952, 97 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    "Third World Trade Union Congress - Item I - Report of activity of the WFTU and the tasks arising for the trade unions in strengthening united action of the workers in the fight for the improvement of their living standards and in defense of peace- Rapporteur: Louis Saillant," October 10-21, 1953, 70 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Third World Trade Union Congress - Point II of the agenda - Report of Brother Giuseppe Di Vittorio, President of the WFTU - Tasks for the trade unions for economic and social development and in the struggle for national independence and democratic liberties in the capitalist and colonial countries - Reporter: G. Di Vittorio," October 10-21, 1953, 42 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions; Speech - Saillant, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    "Third World Trade Union Congress - Item III - Development of the trade union movement in the colonial and semi-colonial countries - Reporter: Ruslan Widjajasastra, General Secretary, Central Bureau of all Indonesian Trade Centre," October 10-21, 1953, 30 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Speech by brother Louis Saillant in concluding the discussion on the first item on the agenda of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress," October 14, 1953, 16 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Speeches - Le Leap, Shvernik, Santi, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    "Speech of Brother Alain Le Leap, General Secretary of the French, CGT," October 12, 1953, 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Speech by N.M. Shvernik, President of the All Union Council of Trade Unions at the 3rd World Trade Union Congress, October 11, 1953, 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Speech by Fernando Santi, Secretary of the Italian General Confederation of Labor," October 13, 1953, 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Unions Congress (WTUC), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Saturday, October 10, 1953," 15 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Sunday, October 11, 1953," 10 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Monday, October 12, 1953," 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Tuesday, October 13, 1953," 16 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Wednesday, October 14, 1953," 10 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Thursday, October 15, 1953," 10 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Friday, October 16, 1953," 19 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Saturday, October 17, 1953," 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Sunday, October 18, 1953," 815 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Monday, October 19, 1953," 16 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Tuesday, October 20, 1953," 7 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    "World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers - 1st item on the agenda - The conditions of the Agricultural and Forestry Workers and their fight for their economic and social demands. Report by the Secretary Ilo Bosi," October 24-28, 1953, 38 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers - 2nd item on the agenda - Strengthening of help to peasants in the fight for their basic instincts - Report by R. Vidimari," October 24-27, 1953, 37 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    "7th Session of the General Council - 1st item - The International Situation and the implementation of the decisions of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress on the development of the unity of the workers in the fight for their demands. Rapporteur: Louis Saillant," December 9-14, 1954, 72 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    "Summary of Louis Saillant's report to the seventh session of the General Council of the WFTU," 1954, 14 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    "Seventh Session of the General Council - Item 1 on the agenda (Appendix) - The development of the struggles for demands throughout the world," December 9-14, 1954, 87 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    "Seventh Session of the General Council - 2nd Item - The charter of Trade Union Rights and the International Campaign to defend and win trade union and democratic rights - Rapporteur: Giuseppe di Vittorio," December 9-14, 1954, 23 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    "Seventh Session of the General Council - Proposed amendments to the definition of the rights to appear in the Charter of Trade Union Rights," December 9-14, 1954, 9 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "General resolution of the seventh session of the General Council of the WFTU." December 9-14, 1954, 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Item II, 2 - Definition of the rights to appear in the Charter of Trade Union Rights," June 26-28, 1954, 7 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "(Draft) Charter of Trade Union Rights," 1954, 7 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Conference of Women Workers (WCWW), 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    "WCWW - 1st item - The united struggle of women workers and trade unions for increases wages, for the application of the principle of equal pay for equal work, against all forms of discrimination, for the improvement of their living conditions the winning of their rights and for peace - by Germaine Guille, Secretary of the French General Confederation of Labor (CGI)," June 14-17, 1956, 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "WCWW - 2nd item - For a more active participation by women in the life and leadership of the trade unions, for large scale trade union recruitment by Tsune Deushi, Head, Women's Department of Teacher's Union of Saitama Prefecture, Japan," June 14-17, 1956, 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    "8th session of the General Council - Report on the 1st item of the agenda - 'Actions for the present economic and social demands of the workers and the development of new trends for unity of the International trade Union movement,' delivered by Louis Saillant, General Secretary, WFTU," September 27-October 3, 1956, 65 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    "8th Session of the General council - report on the 2nd item - 'The trade union movement in countries which have just won their independence or are struggling to win it and fraternal solidarity amongst all workers in the struggle against colonialism,' delivered by Abdoulaye Diallo, Vice President, WFTU," September 27-October 3, 1956, 36 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    "8th Session of the General Council - Report on the main activities of the WFTU," September 27-October 3, 1956, 79 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    "8th Session of the General Council - Report on the convocation of the 4th World Trade Union Congress (4th point of the agenda) - delivered by Giuseppe Casadei," September 27-October 3, 1956, 8 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    "Report of the Delegation of the WFTU to Hungary," November 23-27, 1956, 77 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    "13th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the first item on the agenda - The activities of the WFTU and the preparation of the 4th World Trade Union Congress," January 29-31, 1957, 31 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "13th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the fifth point of the agenda - The development of united action by the workers to achieve their demands in the mines and factories of the European coal and steel community," January 29-31, 1957, 20 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - European trade Union and Workers Conference against the threat of Atomic War and for Peace, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    "Speech by Louis Saillant, General Secretary, World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU)," June 20-22, 1958, 9 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Appeal of the European Trade Union and Workers Conference," June 20-22, 1958, 13 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - First World Conference of Young Workers, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    "Report on 1st point - Wages, vocational training; Young workers trade union and social rights, their struggles and those of the trade union for their demands and against discrimination - Speaker Charles Salducci," July 14-20, 1958, 28 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Report on 2nd item - Prospects for Young Workers throughout the world and their united action for peace against danger of an atomic or thermonuclear war - Presented by Hiroshi Yamakawa," July 14-20, 1958, 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Report on 3rd item - The role of the trade union in organizing and uniting young workers and the part young people play in the strengthening of the trade union - Speaker Lazaro Pena, Secretary of the WFTU," July 14-20, 1958, 18 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
- 1959-1973 (Box 4)
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "19th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the first item on the agenda - Growing tasks of the WFTU in the fight for peace - Speaker: Luigi Grassi, Secretary of the WFTU," April 2-6, 1959, 32 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "19th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the Development of the Workers Economic and Social Demands - Presented by Marcel Bras, Secretary of the WFTU," April 2-6, 1959, 37 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - International Trade Union Committee for Solidarity with the workers and people of Algeria, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Report of the Secretariat of the International Trade Union Committee for solidarity with the workers and people of Algeria - Report on the Solidarity campaigns in the various countries," June-July 1962, 15 page mimeographed typescript. "Speech by the representative of the WFTU, Ibrahin Zakaria, Secretary of the WFTU," June 28-July 1, 1962, 14 page mimeographed typescript.
  - International consultative Trade Union Conference on the Economic and Social Consequences of the European Economic Community and the policy of the monopolies, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "Report presented by Brother Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU," December 14-17, 1962, 94 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Concluding speech by Brother Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU," December 14-17, 1962, 20 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defense and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Trade Union Repression; World Federation of Trade Unions, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    ITU: "2nd Session - Report - Speaker: Edvin Chleboun, Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU)," July 17-19, 1963, 35 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Declaration of the 2nd Session of the International Trade Union and Legal Commission," July 17-19, 1963, 5 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. WFTU: "Press communique - For the defense and extension of trade union rights and for the protection of victims of anti-trade union repression," July 24, 1963, 2 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Federation Syndicale Mondiale (FSM), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    "XIIIeme Session du Conseil General - Rapport - Sur la realisation de la politique unitaire de la FSM pour la defense des interest et des droits des Travailleurs, et lexeme des lutes ouvriers dans le monde, en liaison avec l 'application du Programme d'Action adopted par le Veme Congres Syndical Mondial - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, Secretaire General de la FSM," October 19-24, 1964, 88 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    "13th Session of the General Council (Various conclusions, resolution, and amendment texts)," October 30, 1964, 39 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    "2nd Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against Monopolies. Report on a joint trade union policy for the development of international trade and on the program for organization of a world trade union conference on this subject - Speaker: comrade Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU)," December 14-17, 1964, 60 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "2nd Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against Monopolies - Concluding speech by Brother Louis Saillant," December 14-17, 1964, 10 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    "6th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) Report on the first point of the agenda - Examination of the application o the program of trade union action and steps taken by the WFTU to promote unity, the present evolution and development of the world trade union movement, the new opportunities for unity, solidarity and international trade union relations - Presented by Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU," October 8=22, 1965, 97 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    "6th WTUC - Report on the second item on the agenda - On the development of international trade union solidarity with the struggles of the workers and peoples of the colonial and newly liberated countries for the winning and consolidation of national independence, for independent economic and social development against imperialism, colonialism and neo-colonialism - Presented by Luis Padilla, Secretary of the WFTU," October 8- 22, 1965, 60 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "6th WTUC - Report on the third item on the agenda - The situation in Vietnam and the struggle of the Vietnamese workers and people against the American imperialist aggressors: a) For the Trade Union Federation of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam - Speaker: Brother Hoang Quoc Viet, Chairman of the T.U.F.N.V., Member of the Executive Committee of the World Federation of trade Unions (WFTU)," October 8-22, 1965, 21 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "6th WTUC - Report on the intensification of the war of aggression waged by the American imperialists in South Vietnam and the legitimate patriotic struggle of the South Vietnamese workers and population - Speaker: Tran Hoai Nam, Member of the Permanent Committee of the Central Committee of the Federation of Trade Unions for the Liberation of South Vietnam," October 8-22, 1965, 22 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Federation Syndicale Mondiale, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    "51eme Session du Bureau Executif-Rapport sur la realisation du plan de travail de la FSM en application des decisions du Vieme Congres Syndicale Mondiale - Presente par le cde. Pierre Gensous, Secretaire General - adjoint de la FSM," February 28-March 2, 1966, 51 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    "32nd Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the 1st item on the agenda - WFTU activity and tasks following the 6th WTUC, with special emphasis on solidarity action in support of workers in struggle for economic and social demands, and in support of the workers and people of Vietnam - Report given by Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the WFTU," May 26-28, 1966, 51 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "32nd Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the third item on the agenda - 'The Activities of the TUI's' - Presented by Raul Silvestri, Secretary of the WFTU," May 26-28, 1966, 47 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    "16th Session of the General Council - Report on the first item on the agenda - The activity and tasks of the WFTU since the VI Congress especially with regard to the development of unity, action, and international solidarity on behalf of: the workers and people of Vietnam, the workers struggling for their economic and social demands, the workers and peoples struggling for peace and against imperialism, colonialism, and neo- colonialism - Report of Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the WFTU," December 6-9, 1966, 80 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "16th Session of the General Council General Resolution; Declarations; Decisions (Drafts)," December 6-9, 1966, 36 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.